Never forget why you are the church.
If you're happy, Lord, say amen.
Hey, man, amen.
As we get started this morning, we'll figure things out.
Thank you, Frontline, for leading us and worship as you have.
And, um, you're right, we have nothing.
We have nothing to give the king.
We have nothing but ourselves.
And the good thing about it is, amen, praise, Lord.
Someone's saying, amen.
Golly, that was getting on my nerves.
All right.
Oh, man.
Well, listen, this morning has been good.
And uh, and I'm excited about what God is
going to do this morning.
I can tell you this.
Um, I know that uh, whether who's here, who's not here.
It was funny.
We were talking.
They had a worship concert last night in Murfreesboro.
And we were talking about how, you know, how was the
crowd, how was it and stuff.
And, of course, every time you have something like this, it's
always, man, it could have been better.
And last night we were talking about that and I got to think,
and I said, that's going to be exactly what I think tomorrow morning is that,
man, no matter how many people was here, man, it could have been better.
I can tell you this right now.
It doesn't matter who's here, who's not here.
Guess what?
We're going to hear the word this morning.
Amen.
And so this one I want to look at a parable that may or may not be familiar to you.
So turn your Bibles to Matthew chapter 20.
Matthew chapter 20.
Now, just to give some context, a parable,
to put it simply, is a earthly story with
a heavenly meaning.
If you read scripture, you will very quickly learn,
especially in the gospels, that Jesus was an expert teacher.
Am?
He was the greatest teacher to ever walk the earth.
He would use common, everyday concepts and illustrations
in order to teach a deeper spiritual truth, right?
He would take abstract truths and make them tangible
through familiar scenarios so that people could understand.
Even the disciples, though, at times could not comprehend these parables.
He would be talking about things that they would understand, but they would
miss the deeper heavenly meaning of the message.
So the question is, if that was the case, then why
did Jesus even preach in parables?
Why not just come straight out with the truth?
Why mask deep spiritual things with earthly things?
Well, the answer to this question ought to cause us to tremble,
and you don't have to turn there.
I'm going to read it for you, but disciples ask this very question in Matthew chapter 13.
It says this in starting in verse 10, and the disciples came and said to him,
why do you speak to them in parables?
Jesus answered them.
To you, it has been granted to know the mysteries of the kingdom of God.
But to them it has not been granted.
For whoever has to him or shall be given, and he will have
an abundance, but whoever does not have, even what
he shall what he has shall be taken away from him.
Therefore, I speak to them in parables because while seeing they do not see
and while hearing, they do not hear, nor do they understand in
their case the prophecy of Isaiah's being fulfilled, which says, you
will keep on hearing, but will not understand, you will keep
on seeing, but will not perceive, for the heart of
his people has become dull with their ears, they scarcely
hear, they scarcely hear and they have closed their eyes.
Otherwise, they would see with their eyes, hear with their ears, and
understand with their heart and return, and I would heal them.
But blessed are your eyes.
Because they see.
And your ears, because they hear.
For truly I say to you that many prophets and righteous men desire to
see what you see and then not see it and to hear what you hear and
then not hear it.
Now, right out the gate, if you paid attention for that entire time, say amen.
Amen.
The common question of that is, what in the world, why
this seems unfair to us.
This seems almost like Jesus is pulling a fast one on certain
people to keep them in spiritual blindness.
But here's the truth that Jesus is speaking here.
This is not some arbitrary punishment,
but rather a reflection of spiritual principle.
Those who are receptive to the Lord would gain more understanding,
and those who are already resistant to the Lord would
lose what little comprehension, they did have.
Guys, listen, the truth that we find in scripture that's contrary
to the world is almost always difficult.
See, we want this easy truth, this easy religion.
We want this easy faith.
Let me just tell you something.
There is no such thing as an easy faith that Jesus had to give his life for.
So we have to understand that even though it doesn't seem how we would do
things, God's ways are greater and higher.
See, God will not force himself on you.
If you are here, and I need to warn everybody here today, if
you are here with a hard heart, you may leave here with one as well.
Right here, right now.
You might be hearing your heart as hard as you're thinking, man.
I, you know, I'm already, I'm already irritated.
I know that it's going to be a harvest day.
I don't want to hear an invitation.
Listen, when I was lost, my least favorite part of
any message was the invitation.
I would try to distract myself as much as possible just to get through that time.
Why?
Because I knew I was lost.
And so often, I left their loss, but of course, when I was 18,
I gave my life to Christ, but I want you to know something, and if you're here with
a hard heart, you may leave here with one.
And if you are here to receive, guess what?
You'll receive.
I've learned this about preaching.
My job is to preach.
God's job is to save.
Now, why is this important?
Well, Jesus, after preaching and teaching would say something that he repeated
quite often, you've heard me say it a few times already.
He would say, those that have ears to hear, let them hear.
You may be in here this morning and you are physically in the building, but your heart is far from God.
My prayer is that you turn from that resistant heart posture and humble
yourself before an almighty God.
You may be here and you are walking with the Lord.
My prayer is that your faith is strengthened this morning and you become
even closer with God.
Folks, listen, God has something for each of us here, whether you're lost as you're saved.
If you're lost, listen, you don't have to leave your lost.
Amen.
You can give your life to Christ today.
So knowing this, believing, this, trusting this.
My prayer echoes Jesus' prayer.
Those that have ears to hear, let them hear.
So we're in Matthew 20, uh, with the parable.
We're going to be in verses one.
We're going to read some a lot of scripture here as well, because we got to set the table, okay?
So if you're in Matthew chapter 20, starting in verse one, say, read.
For the kingdom of heaven.
is like a landowner who went out early in the morning to hire laborers for his vineyard.
When he had agreed with the laborers for the Narius for the day, he sent them into his vineyard.
And he went out about the 3rd hour and saw others standing idle in the marketplace.
And to those, he said, you also go into the vineyard, and whatever is right, I will give you.
And so they went, and again, he went out about the 6th and ninth hour and did the same thing.
And about the 11th hour, he went out and found others standing around.
He said to them, why have you been standing here idle all day long?
They said to him because no one hired us.
He said to them, you go into the vineyard too.
When evening came, the owner of the vineyard said to his foreman, call the laborers
and paid their wages, beginning with the last group to the first.
When those hired about the 11th hour came, each one received a denarius.
When those hired 1sts came, they thought that they would receive
more, but each of them also receded an areas, when they received it,
they grumbled at the landowner, saying, these last men have
worked only one hour, and you have made them equal to
us who have borne the burden and the scorching heat of the day.
But he answered and said to one of them, friend, I am doing you no wrong.
Did you not agree with me for denarius?
Take what is yours and go, but I wish to give to the last man the same as to you.
Is it not lawful for me to do what I wish with what is my own?
Or is your eye envious because I am generous?
So the last shall be 1st in the 1st.
Shall be last.
The title this morning is very simple, good gifts, from a good God.
Let's pray, Father, I thank you, Lord, for this morning.
I pray that you allow me to preach and teach with power, clarity, and wisdom.
God, I pray those that have ears to hear, may they hear.
God, I pray the saints are edified.
And God, I pray that the lost are drawn to you.
God show us, Lord, whether it's seed planting, seed watering or harvesting God.
We trust you, we love you.
In Jesus name, pray, ain't everybody say that?
Amen.
This parable starts and ends.
With the same truth.
Matthew 19, verse 30 says, but many who are 1st will be last in the last first.
Matthew verse 20, verse 16.
We just read, so the last shall be 1st and the 1st last.
Now this is completely and utterly contrary to how we see things in the world.
Listen, I like to be first.
Amen?
Does anyone ever do anything competitively wise?
We have a dud of a church.
You can remember that?
No one's ever done any.
Have you ever had a race?
Have you ever done anything?
Like, what are you talking about?
Like, if, listen, I have this saying, if you enjoy to lose, you're a loser.
Okay.
But no, seriously, think about it for a second.
In the world, we want to be first.
Right?
We don't want to be last.
So again, remember, biblical truths are difficult.
They're hard when you compare them to what the world says.
It doesn't make sense.
But it's when you know Christ.
It's when you have the unction of the spirit, that things start to connect.
So in this parable, we see principles that are in
complete opposition to how the world views things.
First, we see their dependency.
See, this landowner went out early in the morning, a typical workday
at this time would have started at 6 a.m., which would be right around sunrise.
So this landowner was out looking for workers before 6
a.m. to work in his vineyard.
The reason he did this was because also at that time, day laborers
would gather in the marketplace, before the start of the work
day, to be available for hire.
These day laborers, now listen to me, this is a very important thing.
These day laborers, typically, were of low social economic
status, and they were most likely unskilled.
They literally had nothing else to do, nothing else to give.
They were just dependent on somebody to give them some kind of work.
In other words, they were desperate.
They were dependent.
These workers were completely dependent on the employers to come and hire
them for the day.
They were all waiting on a chance to get work.
And we see that the landowner did find a group of workers and start at
the 6:00 a.m. hour.
This is where we see their opportunity.
We're gonna move fast this morning, their opportunity.
The Bible says that he agreed to pay the workers at an areas,
which at that time would have been equal to a day's wage.
That's an awesome thing.
If you think about it, these men completely dependent on someone coming
and hiring them out, gets the chance to make a day's way,
so they got to working.
They weren't complaining.
They were very grateful.
They were happy.
They were good with the work.
Man, thank you, landowner.
You are given exactly what I need for today.
Now, obviously, uh, they didn't have enough workers,
so this land owner had a lot more work to do, so three
hours later, he goes back to the marketplace to get more workers.
This would have been 9 a.m., Matthew 20, verse 3 and 4, and he
went about the 3rd hour and saw others standing idol in the marketplace.
And to those, he said, you also go into the venue and
whatever is right, I will give you.
And so they went.
Notice, though, they were standing idle in the marketplace.
They were not working.
They were not trying to, they were just simply standing waiting
for an opportunity.
Either way.
They took it.
Now, there is one difference in the hiring process here, and they did not
agree upon it than there is, but rather, the land owner said
he would pay whatever was right to them.
And since they started at 9 instead of six, probably they expected less pay.
So this landowner must have had a large vineyard because he
ends up going back to the marketplace to hire more workers many times.
Again, he went out about the 6th and ninth hour and did the same thing.
So he's gone out and hired at 6 a.m.
He's hired at 9 AM.
He's hired at noon and 3 p.m.
All these people doing the same work just at different times.
But there are still workers that were needed.
So Matthew chapter 20, verse 6 and 7 says, and about the
11th hour he went out, and found others standing around, and he
said to them, why have you been standing here idle all day long?
They said to him because no one hired us.
He said to them, you go into the vineyard too.
Now the 11th hour would have been at 5 p.m.
One hour before the work day was done.
We see that all throughout the day, there was opportunity for as many who were
willing to come to the vineyard and work, and guess what?
Now, it is pay time.
Anyone like payday?
Y'all like getting paid money for your work?
Amen?
Me too.
So it says when evening came, the owner of the vineyard said to his foreman,
call the laborers and pay them their wages, beginning with the last group.
to the 1st group.
Now, you gotta think about this for a second.
The ones that got hired at five, they're probably barely sweating.
They're not as grimy, they're not as dirty.
They're probably coming in, man.
What a day.
Let's go get some pay, right?
That's what we would call a blister.
They show up when the work's done.
Amen?
I've been called that a few times here at this church and it hurts my feelings, not any of it.
No, I didn't hurt my feelings.
But here's what happened.
So, they came out, and when I was hired about the 11th hour, that's
5 p.m., he gave me the narius.
Now, let's be, let's not be dishonest this morning.
Just think about this for a second.
If you were there at this time, you saw the workers who had worked for one hour,
get a whole day's pay, what would you expect?
You'd expect some big payday, wouldn't you?
Because that's how the world sees things.
I earn what I get.
Right?
I put in, I input the work.
And then I get the reward.
I'm about to get a serious payday.
I mean, they got a whole day's pay.
I'll get 2 or three.
I've been here since 6 a.m.
Surely.
That's not what happened, though.
So, Matthew 20, verse 10 and 12.
When those hired first came, they thought they would receive more.
But each of them also receded than areas, and when they received it, they grumbled at the landowner.
Saying these last men have worked only one hour, and you have made
them equal to us, who have borne the burden in the scorching heat of the day.
Why do they get the same as me?
We worked all day in here in this heat?
And you're telling me that we're getting equal pay.
Guys, if there's anything I know about this generation of young workers,
They're not about that equal pay stuff, right?
They want to get paid more.
They want to work for a year somewhere and then own the company.
Like, that's kind of, that's that's the audacity that we have in this, in this situation, right?
People say, man, how long you been in Cedar growth?
A long, long time.
I remember when I made very, very little.
I remember when it was very little people here, all the things, guess what?
Sometimes you just got to stick with something.
Amen?
That's free advice to whoever needs it.
But here's the thing.
They think, and they say, literally, they're hard posture.
You have made them equal with us.
Now, church, what we see here is not just
the dependability, not not just, but also his impartiality.
We see the dependability, the opportunity, but also
his impartiality.
There are 2 religions in the world.
There's many thoughts of religion, there's many different ways it
can be manifested, but there's only 2 religions in the entire world.
The 1st is one that stems all the way back to Cain, and that is work based.
If I can do enough, if I can be enough, if I can save up
enough spiritual equity, God will let me in heaven.
It's a work-based salvation.
It's the same thing when Cain, when he didn't like that God rejected
his offering and received Abel's.
He got mad in pride.
He killed his brother.
He got banished.
And what did he do?
He tried to prove to everyone, I don't need God.
I'm going to build this city.
And so we have a work-based salvation.
By the way, if you can earn your salvation, you don't have it.
Every false religion today can be traced back to some form of work based salvation.
True salvation is grace based.
Grace is the great equalizer.
Grace is not earned, only given.
We were talking, I went to dinner on Friday night with some people.
And we were talking about the, you know, different backgrounds and testimonies
and stuff, and, and, you know, me and Heather, we grew up in,
uh, going to church, and we met it at church, and we
got married, and, and, you know, I became a preacher really quickly,
all the things, and, and it's funny how it's like, man, one of them
said, well, we don't have that clean of a past, you know, and they started just kind of,
you know, sharing some stuff.
And the beautiful part about it is, my salvation is
the same as their salvation, because it's the same Jesus who saved us.
So it doesn't matter where you come from, doesn't matter what you've
done, who you've done it with.
Grace is the great equalizer.
You have to have Jesus no matter what to be born again.
We see this in Ephesians chapter 2, verse 8 through 10,
for by grace you have been saved through faith, and that not of yourselves.
It is the gift of God, not as a result of work so that
you may not boast.
Let me tell you something.
If I could get to heaven based on what I've done.
You know what I do when I get there, I brag about it.
I'm just going to let you know right now you say, oh, well, preacher, you're not spiritual.
No, no, no, what I'm trying to tell you is, if I could earn my way to heaven,
Think about that.
If I had a bigger golden part, a driveway
than you did, I'd be like, you know how I got that?
This is what I did.
I did this, I did this.
I preached for, you know, 40, 50 years, and hopefully that'd be great.
Amen.
But I've done all this stuff and I earned my way into heaven.
That's not how it works.
We are to boast because we've done nothing for it.
Verse 10, for we are his workmanship created in Christ Jesus
for good works, which God prepared beforehand so that we would walk in them.
Listen, if you want to do good works,
It is based on our response to God's grace.
Listen, I don't give my life to all the works of the ministry because
I'm trying to earn something.
I give my life to the works of the ministry because I've been saved by Jesus.
That's why.
This work-based mindset can easily deceive, even those who know Christ if we're not careful.
We try to, we try to mark off the list of the things that we're
supposed to do, and before you know it, listen, I've fallen in this trap so often.
We get so busy with ministry that we miss Jesus.
So now in this parable, we see that there are many workers who get hired on
for the work in the venue, the landowner represents
God, and the workers represents those who are saved.
The vineyard is the world that we are to serve Christ in.
So how did they land on a response to the grumbling?
Well, in verse 13, but he answered instead of them.
Friend, I'm doing you no wrong.
Did you not agree with me for the denarius?
Take what is yours and go, but I wish to give to this last man the same as to you.
Is it not lawful for me to do what I wish with what is my own?
Was it that your eye is envious because I am generous?
So the last shall be 1st and the 1st last.
See, when you own it all, you can do what you want with it.
Amen?
Understand what I'm saying?
Anyone got kids?
Anyone, like, anyone like that you got kids?
My goodness gracious.
Mercy.
I'm feeling what you feeling.
So if you got kids, you know what I'm about to say?
Listen, there's times to where we'll like be eating some snacks or whatever.
And in our house, we have those little white Cheeto puffs.
They want to talk about, they're like healthier than the Cheeto stuff, but they're
like the white, little white cheddar stuff, and they're little puffs.
No one knows what I'm talking about.
Y'all getting on my nerves this morning.
Woo!
So man, I'll just sit there and I eat them.
I'm talking and I'll give, you know, the girl one, you know what I'm saying?
And they're like, man, I want more.
I'll give them a few more.
I said, okay, y'all done.
And they're like, what do you mean?
I said, y'all have eaten too many.
I said, so slip back on this couch and let's watch, you know, Duck Dynasty.
And so we'll be sitting there and, and I, and then I'll just kind of open the bag back up.
And they look at me like, Dad, that's not fair.
Don't you loving your kid says that?
After not having one bill in the world.
Yeah.
I just tell him a simple talent, baby.
Life ain't fair.
I said, I own this bag of Cheetos.
I can eat as many or as little as I want.
And you're gonna get what I get.
And guess what?
What I give you, be grateful for.
Now, what I'm trying to say is this.
As silly as that is, right, as lighthearted
as that illustration was that our example was, God owns it all.
You don't think that I've thought, sometimes why is our church not big as that church?
It doesn't matter.
God is working here.
God is working there.
The way he works, hey, that's up to him.
Why are they getting something in their life that I'm not getting?
It doesn't matter.
guess what?
By the way, if we stop looking, uh, comparison is a thief of joy.
We start comparing ourselves to everyone else, we might have a little bit of a happier countenance.
And so what I'm trying to say is this.
Look, when we understand that, man, they got a day's pay.
They were out in the marketplace desperate for work, and they got exactly what they needed.
And now all of a sudden, just because someone else got what.
they, want to grumble and complain and gripe.
And so God, and so God gives us the truth.
So the last shall be first, and the first shall be last.
He owns it all.
He can do what he wants with it.
I like how this home and New Testament commentary explains this.
Jesus revealed here.
The way we as humans think about what is fair and just.
When we see rewards handed out in heaven, we are sure to
be in for some surprises.
Some of the people and ministries that we have deemed insignificant will be celebrated.
While many of the more prominent people in their ministries will receive little recognition.
It is not Jesus' purpose here to explain the criteria he uses
for such decisions, but only to warn us against false
assumptions and expectations.
Jesus made the point that heaven's rewards are based upon God's
standard, in our faithfulness, to our calling, in both attitude
and action.
There will be no negotiating with technicalities to consider.
In other words, God, I give you what you need.
The real, the simple truth is this, Romans 211, for there is no partiality
with God.
We are all dependent on him for our salvation.
We are all given the same opportunity, through the gospel.
Don't you love how this parable shows God as the one who goes
out and seeks those who needs work?
In other words, we know that, listen, God, in Luke
19, verse 10, this should sound familiar.
Jesus said for the Son of Man has come to seek and
to save that which was lost.
Now, I want us to think about it just for a moment.
This could be the most important moment of someone's life this morning.
Now, we talked about their dependency.
We've talked about our opportunity.
We talked about God's impartiality.
But there's another part I want us to notice, and it's something that many will overlook.
Notice this, their availability.
If these workers had not been in the marketplace available to work that day,
Regardless of their start time, then they've been hard.
Is that pretty simple truth, understand?
Do you know what keeps so many people from God?
They are too busy living for anything or anyone else.
They are already hired out by this world system.
They do not make themselves available to God.
Our need for availability does not alter or limit God's power
and authority in salvation, scripture makes it
clear in Romans 1013, for whoever will call
on the name of the Lord, will be saved.
You say, how much atonement was given at Calvary.
Here's how much atonement was given to Calvary.
If every single person has ever lived on this earth since
ever, would call upon the name of the Lord for salvation,
there's enough atonement to save every single one of them.
That's what I believe about atonement right there.
The enemy has gotten too many to believe that they can wait.
They can they can get right.
Man, I have someone that I love and I love dearly that has
told me over and over again when this time of my life happens.
When I get to this phase of my life, when I'm done
grinding in the world, I'll give my time to Jesus.
Let me just tell you something.
If you're not willing to give your time to Christ now.
If you're not willing to give your life to Christ now, what
makes you think you will tomorrow?
Remember Pharaoh and Exodus.
Guys, listen, this is this is sobering right here.
God was sending plagues upon Egypt in order to show his power and
convince Pharaoh to let his people go and, and listen, this is one of those,
uh, uh, age old debates on, well, who hardened
Pharaoh's heart and who this and who that and all the things, and that's not even
what I'm talking about, but it's very clear what happens in this situation.
So the 1st plague was Moses turning the Nile into blood, and
the 2nd was an infestation of frogs.
Exodus 8, 8, 9 says, then Pharaoh called from Moses,
and Aaron said, entreat the Lord that he removed the frogs
from me and from my people, and I will let the people go that
they may sacrifice to the Lord.
In other words, what he's saying is okay, enough is enough.
I will submit to what your God says.
Moses said the pharaoh, the honor is yours to tell me, when,
when, shall I entreat for you and your
servants and your people that the frogs be destroyed from you and your houses?
They may be left only in denial.
Now.
Let's not miss this for a 2nd.
Pharaoh was about to get exactly what he's asked for.
Remove these frogs.
I'm done with it.
I can't I can't handle it no more.
I'm understanding what's going on here, so we move them,
and you can do exactly what God has told you you need to do.
I'm submitting to what your God has said.
And then Moses said, when?
His answer ought to reverberate through our hearts and minds today.
Exodus 8, verse 10.
Then he said, Tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Moses, you got to get these frogs out of here.
Our life is falling apart and we need some help here.
So would your God do something for us and yeah, you you
know, you can do what you want and you can go out and sacrifice him.
Moses says, when?
Tomorrow.
Listen this morning, folks, if you read your Bible, you know what came tomorrow.
There were 10 plagues.
This was the 2nd one.
Why was there 10?
Because he waited till tomorrow.
Are y'all are y'all missing this this morning?
Listen, if he would have just submitted the God's will then, it'd been over.
So God sent the rest of the plagues and Pharaoh end up losing his firstborn son,
and his life in the Red Sea.
All because he waited until tomorrow.
Preacher, you are oversimplifying this.
Am I?
What does scripture say about salvation in 2nd Corinthians 6, verse 2.
For he says at the acceptable time I listened to you.
And on the day of salvation, I helped you.
Behold, now, is the acceptable time.
Behold, now is the day of salvation.
Well, I don't want to miss out on anything.
And if I give my life to Christ now, what if I lose certain
things that I hold there, there's just too much stuff.
There's so many changes that I had to make, and I'm
just too ingrained in the world, and look, God is gracious.
So when I get older and when I'm done and I'll
give my life to Christ, tomorrow, preacher, tomorrow.
I want to leave you with a story today.
And it's a story that's based on actual people.
I'm not going to use names, but...
I was listening to the deeper podcast, Pastor Joey Martin.
if you need a good podcast.
I just gave you one, write it down, listen to it.
Um, and man, it stirred my heart.
There was a father whose son was young.
And struggled in school a little bit, but on that semester,
man, he his son got straight A's.
Anyone ever got straight A's?
That's what I thought.
Anyway.
But no, his son got straight A's, and so his dad was so proud
of his son, and so he said, you know what?
He took him to, um, a toy store,
a toy store, and told him to pick out anything he wanted.
He said, You've done so good this semester that you can get anything you want.
And so they walk into that toy store, and, Man, that young
boy, he is overwhelmed with the options.
overwhelmed with the choices that he has to make.
I mean, there's toys over here.
There's tours over there.
And his dad said, Hey, you can get whatever you want.
Seeing all the toys everywhere.
He embraced his father's leg and held it real tight.
The boy looked up at his daddy.
The big smile and said, Daddy, why don't
you pick out for me.
You always choose the best gifts.
Listen to me today.
Our God always makes.
The best choices for us.
He knows what we need.
Every good and perfect gift comes from him.
He works all things together for good of those who love him.
and are called according to his person.
According to his purpose.
My question is simple, are you trusting him?
With your life.
Are you trusting him with his choices?
You know, we say all the time in preacher talk that
if you just make your decision,
Based on God's word, guess what?
The decision goes away.
Now it's just submitting to him.
In other words, you know, some people got up this morning debating whether they're going to go to church or not.
They may or may not be here.
But if you make a decision, hey, it's the Lord's day.
going.
guess what?
You will be here.
We make our decisions based on what God says about things.
And so what I'm trying to say this morning is very simple.
If you're here, And you don't know the Lord Jesus.
And you're thinking there's no way I can give up what I have.
I like my life the way it is.
I like my sin.
My preacher growing up, he called pet sins.
I like the things that I do that are wrong.
I know they're wrong, but I just, I enjoy, and we would never
say it out loud, but that's what we're saying in our hearts.
Listen, when you reject the almighty, good God, for
your sin, you're saying my sin is better than God.
But we know that he gives the best gifts.
So my question is simple this morning.
What if We are in the 11th hour.
And you might say, oh, here we go, preacher manipulation.
Preacher, you know, preacher talk right here.
They're going to try to scare me into salvation.
Can I tell you something?
And a lot, listen, a lot of you know this, and I'm not trying.
I'm not trying to to draw any emotions because it's,
it's, it's emotional for me, but 2 Tuesdays
ago, I never would have thought that we lost, who we lost in our family.
Guys will not promise tomorrow.
My loved one didn't wake up thinking that she was gonna see Jesus face
to face that day, but she did.
What if we're in the 11th hour?
Our God gives good gifts.
Call upon his name today, and if you're here this morning and you are saved.
Are you comparing your walk and your life to everything else?
Are you tallying?
The good things that you've done?
Are you trying to keep score?
Just serve the king.
You do realize.
That when you serve Jesus.
You are literally in the highest place you can be in life.
So just serve the king.
But hands-bound eyes closed off this place.
I wonder if some of us need to be like that young boy.
Who looked up at his daddy and said, Daddy, you pick for me because...
You always make the good choices.
Maybe you need to trust your heavenly Father today.
Maybe the Holy Spirit right now is drawing you under Christ
in such a way that you know you're lost.
And you need Jesus, all the things that you thought would would keep
you, all the things that you were worried about before, they're
fading out of you because the Holy Spirit is speaking to
you and drawing you unto salvation.
The Bible says that if you confess with your mouth that Jesus is Lord
and believe in your heart that God raised him in the dead, you
will be saved.
Let's not overcomplicate this.
The work was done in Calvary.
Jesus lived, died, and rose again.
Do you believe it?
And if so, will you confess him as Lord?
Maybe you're here and you're a Christian and you are.
your comparing every little thing.
You're irritated this person from being successful.
You're irritated at that.
Listen, we talked about it 2 or 3 weeks ago.
We have to rejoice when others rejoice.
That's what brotherly and sisterly love looks like in the family of God.
So maybe you need to repent of that prideful mindset.
And get right with God this morning.